When you can live forever, what do you live for?
Twilight is a fantasy, drama, romance film directed by Catherine Hardwicke.
When Bella Swan moves to a small town in the Pacific Northwest, she falls in love with Edward
Cullen, a mysterious classmate who reveals himself to be a 108-year-old vampire.
Despite Edward's repeated cautions, Bella can't stay away from
him, a fatal move that endangers her own life.
Bella Swan, played by Kristen Stewart.
Edward Cullen, played by Robert Pattinson.
Charlie Swan, played by Billy Burke.
Dr. Carlisle Cullen, played by Peter Facinelli.
Alice Cullen, played by Ashley Greene.
Jasper, played by Jackson Rathbone.
Twilight is a 2008 American vampire romantic fantasy film directed by Catherine Hardwicke from a
screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2005 novel of the same name by Stephenie Meyer.
It is the first installment in The Twilight Saga film series.
The film stars Kristen Stewart as Bella Swan, a teenage girl,
and Robert Pattinson as Edward Cullen, a vampire.
It focuses on the development of Bella and Edward's relationship and the subsequent efforts
of Edward and his family to keep Bella safe from another coven of vampires.
The project was in development for approximately three years at Paramount Pictures' MTV Films, during
which time a film adaptation that differed significantly from the novel was written.
Summit Entertainment acquired the rights to the novel
after the project's stagnant development.
Rosenberg wrote a new adaptation of the novel shortly before the 2007–2008 Writers Guild
of America strike and sought to be faithful to the novel's storyline.
Principal photography began in March 2008 and took 44 days, being completed in
May; the film was shot in the states of Oregon and Washington.
Twilight premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Westwood, California on November 17, 2008, and was
theatrically released in the United States on November 21, by Summit Entertainment.
Despite receiving mixed reviews from critics, the
film grossed $412 million worldwide.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray on March 21, 2009, and
became the most purchased DVD of the year.
The soundtrack was released on November 4, 2008.
The film was followed by four sequels: New Moon (2009), Eclipse (2010),
Breaking Dawn – Part 1 (2011), and Breaking Dawn – Part 2 (2012)
The film explores themes of high school, soulmates, based
on novel or book, immortality, vampire.
The tone is emotional.